HOWARD LYNCH

CONTACT



Online Portfolio https://thegrinch1985.github.i o, Howard, Lynch



(Home/Mobile +353 862185243



howielynch@gmail.com

SKILLS

- · Proficient user of Angular, C#
- · SQL queries to intermediate level using **SOL-Server**
- · Designing and developing websites using Angular, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap
- · Competent user of Windows and Linux Operating Systems.
- · Competent user of Linux Terminal
- · Capable of resolving hardware and software-based issues
- · Experience of using version control systems GIT and SVN
- · Experience of using Microsoft Azure
- · Understanding of software designs patterns and the principles object orientated design
- · Logical, Analytical, and creative approach to problems

REFERENCES

REFERENCES

Jimmy Bryden Technical Project Manager VHI Group Services DAC Jimmy.bryden@vhi.ie 0868591885

Frank Sullivan It Solutions Head of Automation 0858514818 Frank.sullivan@sqs.com

Currently working for BearingPoint in Dublin as a Software Engineer. Working at BearingPoint has really helped me improve my skill set, adding modern front-end frameworks like Angular, and Cloud services like Microsoft Azure to my areas of expertise. Can learn quickly and enjoy teaching what I know to others. Fantastic collaborator with excellent interpersonal and IT-based skills. Can produce necessary results required when on a deadline, as I have done at VHI, BearingPoint & BMW. I feel I can be an excellent addition to any team, especially one requiring an ambitious and motivated character. Support given to me will be reciprocated in the form of hard work and dedication to the task(s) at hand.

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2019 to Current

Software Developer

BearingPoint

- · Currently working at BearingPoint Dublin as a Software Developer
- · Using Angular, C#, Azure Dev Ops, SQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Cypress
- · Working knowledge of front-end optimization and performance techniques
- Designed & wrote Integration tests & Unit tests for front end Angular & Cypress
- · Make design recommendations towards the development of new code or reuse of existing code
- · Crisp communication with clients and work as an interface between team members and client counterpart
- · Play key role in structuring our single page applications to make them easy to maintain and to ensure they are highly modularized
- · Worked as part of a 40-person team with agile development and using version control GIT
- · Developed new, efficient, and well-tested code for a variety of different projects
- Worked with CI/CD
- Resolved Merge Conflicts, configured triggers and queued new builds within the release pipeline.

January 2018 to September 2018

Software Development Intern

VHI Healthcare

- · Began a work placement in February with VHI and it was a fantastic experience for me.
- · It improved my understanding of the inner workings of IT, as used in the business world, whilst also understanding the necessary requirements for building and structuring IT projects, both alone and in a team.

EDUCATION

2019

Bachelor of Science in Computing & Software Development (2.1 result)

Technology University of Dublin

September 2014 - June 2015

Computer Science FETAC level

Blackrock College of Further Education, BFEI

BEARINGPOINT PROJECTS

BMW - ATS

Autonomous Transport Systems is a platform to manage various vehicles that can navigate autonomously inside a production facility. The system contains several services deployed into Microsoft Azure with vehicles connecting through Azure IoT Hub. Its design was a front-end of angular & back-end of .NET. I learned a lot on this project. I mainly was involved in the frontend development of the application, but I also contributed into the testing of backend development and some docker tasks.

Med-Regulate – Case Management System

Med-Regulate was based on Eolas, but the idea was to modernize the Eolas application with up-to-date technology. This project was also a case management system, in a .NET solution which integrates with SharePoint & Match point to enable the client to handle the application process of a company looking to sell pharmaceutical products in Ireland with an angular 8 front end, C#, back end & also a SQL server. This project was hosted on azure dev ops and used a lot of the version control features, such as pipelines etc.

Eolas – Case Management System

Developer on Eolas project for HPRA implementing a case management system in a .NET solution which integrates with SharePoint & Match point to enable the client to handle the application process of a company looking to sell pharmaceutical products in Ireland. This was an interesting project to start off with and I learned a lot from this position. This was built with Sharepoint2013, Entity Framework 6, auto Mapper for mapping objects in a Domain Driven Design Pattern.

